# Subhajit Chaudhury

CONTACT INFORMATION Website: subhajitchaudhury.github.io

- 040EE4EE

Email: subhajitiitb14@gmail.com

Information

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/subhajit-chaudhury-24955455

**Phone:** +81-7021837790

RESEARCH Interest My research interest lies at the intersection of reinforcement learning, computer vision and robust machine learning. At IBM Research, I work on reinforcement learning algorithms applied to dialog-based systems and imitation learning from videos. In my Ph.D. thesis, my goal is to develop learning mathed a in deep neural networks that are robust against adversarial attacks.

methods in deep neural networks that are robust against adversarial attacks.

EDUCATION

## The University of Tokyo, Japan

April 2018 - March 2021

Ph.D., EECS, Graduate School of Information Science and Technology

Advised by Prof. Toshihiko Yamasaki

**Topic:** Robust machine learning against adversarial attacks.

# Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Bombay, India

July 2012 - June 2014

M.Tech, Department of Electrical Engineering

GPA: 9.81 out of 10

**Topic:** Efficient deformable 3D graphics rendering for real-time Haptics applications.

# Jadavpur University, India

July 2008 - June 2012

B.E.(Hons.) Department of Electrical Engineering

GPA: 8.90 out of 10 (Rank: 3<sup>rd</sup>/125)

**Topic:** Vision-based indoor structure discovery for locomotion in autonomous robots.

Work Experience

#### Research Scientist, IBM Research, Tokyo

April 2017- Present

**Topics:** Reinforcement learning in dialog-based systems, adversarial imitation learning from video demonstrations, weakly supervised event detection in sports videos.

# Researcher, NEC Central Research Lab, Tokyo

Oct 2014- March 2017

**Topic:** Deep learning-based infrastructure surveillance using computer vision methods. Our vision-based crack detection system was deployed in real-life applications.

### Teaching Assistant, IIT Bombay

July 2012 - June 2014

**Responsibilities:** Held recitations, organized exams and evaluated papers for the courses on Signals and System, Digital Signal Processing and Computer Vision.

# SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- 1) Subhajit Chaudhury, Daiki Kimura, Kartik Talamadupula, Michiaki Tatsubori, Asim Munawar and Ryuki Tachibana, Bootstrapped Q-learning with Context Relevant Observation Pruning to Generalize in Text-based Games, EMNLP, 2020.
- 2) Subhajit Chaudhury and Toshihiko Yamasaki, Investigating Generalization in Neural Networks under Optimally Evolved Training Perturbations, IEEE ICASSP, 2020.
- 3) Subhajit Chaudhury, Understanding Generalization in Neural Networks for Robustness against Adversarial Vulnerabilities, AAAI 2020, Ph.D. thesis presentation.
- 4) Daiki Kimura, Subhajit Chaudhury, Minori Narita, Asim Munawar, and Ryuki Tachibana, Adversarial Discriminative Attention for Robust Anomaly Detection, IEEE WACV, 2020.
- **5)** Subhajit Chaudhury, Daiki Kimura, Phongtharin Vinayavekhin, Asim Munawar, Ryuki Tachibana, Koji Ito, Yuki Inaba, Minoru Matsumoto, Shuji Kidokoro, and Hiroki Ozaki, **Unsupervised Tem-**

poral Feature Aggregation for Event Detection in Unstructured Sports Videos, IEEE ISM, Dec 2019. (Long paper)

- 6) Daiki Kimura, Subhajit Chaudhury, Ryuki Tachibana and Sakyasingha Dasgupta, Internal Model from Observations for Reward Shaping, ICML Adaptive and Learning Agents (ALA) 2018; AAAI Reinforcement Learning in Games, 2019.
- 7) Phongtharin Vinayavekhin, Subhajit Chaudhury, Asim Munawar, Don Joven Agravante, Giovanni De Magistris, Daiki Kimura and Ryuki Tachibana, Focusing on What is Relevant: Time-Series Learning and Understanding using Attention, International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR), 2018.
- 8) Tadanobu Inoue, Subhajit Chaudhury, Giovanni De Magistris and Sakyasingha Dasgupta, Transfer learning from synthetic to real images using variational auto-encoders for robotic applications, IEEE ICIP, 2018.
- 9) Subhajit Chaudhury, Sakyasingha Dasgupta, Asim Munawar, Md. S. Khan and Ryuki Tachibana, Conditional generation of multi-modal data using constrained embedding space mapping, ICML, Implicit Generative Models, 2017.
- 10) Subhajit Chaudhury, Gaku Nakano, Jun Takada, Akihiko Iketani, Spatial-temporal motion field analysis for crack detection on concrete surfaces, IEEE WACV 2017.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, C++, Java
- Machine learning Tools: Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras, scikit-learn
- Tools: Matlab, ROS, Gazebo, OpenCV, CUDA, OpenGL

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Won Scholarship to present my Ph.D. thesis at AAAI in New York, USA.
- Obtained Best Paper Award (1st in 126 accepted papers) and Best Presentation Award at Symposium on Sensing via Image Information (SSII), 2019.
- Received **Best student paper**, honorable mention (out of 321 papers) at MIRU **2019**, a top domestic Computer Vision conference in Japan.
- Invited Talk on "Visual Imitation Learning for Autonomous Control" at NASA, Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL), Dec 2019.
- Secured All India Rank 33 out of 110,125 students in Electrical Engineering, GATE-2012.
- Secured rank 86/80,000 in West Bengal Joint Entrance Examination, 2008 for Engineering.

Media Coverage

- My work on weakly supervised rally detection in table tennis videos received multiple media coverage: Nikkei Voicy, Softbank Creative Business+IT, Nikkan Kogyo Shimbun, ZDNet and Hokkaido Shimbun. This work is being used by the Japan Institute of Sports Sciences (JISS) for training of the national table tennis team.
- My work on vision-based crack detection was used for runway inspection in Japan which was covered by Nikkei newspaper.

Professional Activities

- Reviewer for ICRA2018, IROS2018, IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM), 2018, IJCAI 2019, ECML-PKDD 2019, ICRA2020, CVPR2021.
- Program Committee member for IJCAI2020, AAAI2020 and KBRL workshop for IJCAI 2020.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Executive Council member of IIT Bombay Alumni Association in Tokyo from 2015.
- Passed Japanese Language Proficiency Test, N4 level. (Ability have general conversations)
- IIT Bombay swimming club member and participated in various swimming competitions.